{"passage": ["When it comes to energy, everyone loves efficiency. Cutting", "energy waste is one of those goals that both sides of the political", "divide can agree on, even if they sometimes diverge on how best to", "get there. Energy efficiency allows us to get more out of our given", "resources, which is good for the economy and (mostly) good for", "the environment as well. In an increasingly hot and crowded world,", "the only sustainable way to live is to get more out of less. Every", "environmentalist would agree.", "But change the conversation to food, and suddenly efficiency", "doesn\u2019t look so good. Conventional industrial agriculture has", "become incredibly efficient on a simple land to food basis. Thanks", "to fertilizers, mechanization and irrigation, each American farmer", "feeds over 155 people worldwide. Conventional farming gets more", "and more crop per square foot of cultivated land\u2014over 170 bushels", "of corn per acre in Iowa, for example\u2014which can mean less", "territory needs to be converted from wilderness to farmland. And", "since a third of the planet is already used for agriculture\u2014destroying", "forests and other wild habitats along the way\u2014anything", "that could help us produce more food on less land would seem to", "be good for the environment.", "Of course, that\u2019s not how most environmentalists regard their", "arugula [a leafy green]. They have embraced organic food as better", "for the planet\u2014and healthier and tastier, too\u2014than the stuff", "produced by agricultural corporations. Environmentalists disdain", "the enormous amounts of energy needed and waste created by", "conventional farming, while organic practices\u2014forgoing artificial", "fertilizers and chemical pesticides\u2014are considered far more", "sustainable. Sales of organic food rose 7.7% in 2010, up to $26.7", "billion\u2014and people are making those purchases for their", "consciences as much as their taste buds.", "Yet a new meta-analysis in Nature does the math and comes to a", "hard conclusion: organic farming yields 25% fewer crops on", "average than conventional agriculture. More land is therefore", "needed to produce fewer crops\u2014and that means organic farming", "may not be as good for the planet as we think.", "In the Nature analysis, scientists from McGill University in", "Montreal and the University of Minnesota performed an analysis of", "66 studies comparing conventional and organic methods across 34", "different crop species, from fruits to grains to legumes. They found", "that organic farming delivered a lower yield for every crop type,", "though the disparity varied widely. For rain-watered legume crops", "like beans or perennial crops like fruit trees, organic trailed", "conventional agriculture by just 5%. Yet for major cereal crops like", "corn or wheat, as well as most vegetables\u2014all of which provide", "the bulk of the world\u2019s calories\u2014conventional agriculture", "outperformed organics by more than 25%.", "The main difference is nitrogen, the chemical key to plant", "growth. Conventional agriculture makes use of 171 million metric", "tons of synthetic fertilizer each year, and all that nitrogen enables", "much faster plant growth than the slower release of nitrogen from", "the compost or cover crops used in organic farming. When we talk", "about a Green Revolution, we really mean a nitrogen revolution\u2014along", "with a lot of water.", "But not all the nitrogen used in conventional fertilizer ends up", "in crops\u2014much of it ends up running off the soil and into the", "oceans, creating vast polluted dead zones. We\u2019re already putting", "more nitrogen into the soil than the planet can stand over the long", "term. And conventional agriculture also depends heavily on", "chemical pesticides, which can have unintended side effects.", "What that means is that while conventional agriculture is more", "efficient\u2014sometimes much more efficient\u2014than organic farming,", "there are trade-offs with each. So an ideal global agriculture", "system, in the views of the study\u2019s authors, may borrow the best", "from both systems, as Jonathan Foley of the University of", "Minnesota explained:", "The bottom line? Today\u2019s organic farming practices are", "probably best deployed in fruit and vegetable farms, where", "growing nutrition (not just bulk calories) is the primary goal. But", "for delivering sheer calories, especially in our staple crops of", "wheat, rice, maize, soybeans and so on, conventional farms have", "the advantage right now.", "Looking forward, I think we will need to deploy different kinds", "of practices (especially new, mixed approaches that take the best of", "organic and conventional farming systems) where they are best", "suited\u2014geographically, economically, socially, etc."], "question_set": [{"question": "As used in line 11\n(\u201csimple\u201d)\n, \u201csimple\u201d most nearly means", "answers": ["straightforward.", "modest.", "unadorned.", "easy."], "correct_answer_index": 0, "category": "Vocabulary in Context Question"}, {"question": "According to the passage, a significant attribute of conventional agriculture is its ability to", "answers": ["produce a wide variety of fruits and vegetables.", "maximize the output of cultivated land.", "satisfy the dietary needs of the world\u2019s population.", "lessen the necessity of nitrogen in plant growth."], "correct_answer_index": 1, "category": "Detail Question"}, {"question": "Which choice best reflects the perspective of the \u201cenvironmentalists\u201d (line 21\n(\u201cenvironmentalists\u201d)\n) on conventional agriculture?", "answers": ["It produces inferior fruits and vegetables and is detrimental to the environment.", "It is energy efficient and reduces the need to convert wilderness to farmland.", "It is good for the environment only in the short run.", "It depletes critical resources but protects wildlife habitats."], "correct_answer_index": 0, "category": "Inference Question"}, {"question": "Which choice provides the best evidence for the answer to the previous question?", "answers": ["lines 21\u201322 (\u201cOf course... green\u201d)\n(\u201cOf course, that\u2019s not how most environmentalists regard their arugula [a leafy green].\u201d)", "lines 22\u201324 (\u201cThey... corporations\u201d)\n(\u201cThey have embraced organic food as better for the planet\u2014and healthier and tastier, too\u2014than the stuff produced by agricultural corporations.\u201d)", "lines 24\u201328 (\u201cEnvironmentalists...sustainable\u201d)\n(\u201cEnvironmentalists disdain the enormous amounts of energy needed and waste created by conventional farming, while organic practices\u2014forgoing artificial fertilizers and chemical pesticides\u2014are considered far more sustainable.\u201d)", "lines 33\u201335 (\u201cMore... think\u201d)\n(\u201cMore land is therefore needed to produce fewer crops\u2014and that means organic farming may not be as good for the planet as we think.\u201d)"], "correct_answer_index": 1, "category": "Evidence Support Question"}, {"question": "Which statement best expresses a relationship between organic farming and conventional farming that is presented in the passage?", "answers": ["Both are equally sustainable, but they differ dramatically in the amount of land they require to produce equivalent yields.", "Both rely on artificial chemicals for pest control, but organic farmers use the chemicals sparingly in conjunction with natural remedies.", "Both use nitrogen to encourage plant growth, but the nitrogen used in conventional farming comes from synthetic sources.", "Both create a substantial amount of nitrogen runoff, but only the type of nitrogen found in fertilizers used in conventional farming can be dangerous."], "correct_answer_index": 2, "category": "Inference Question"}, {"question": "Which choice provides the best evidence for the answer to the previous question?", "answers": ["lines 10\u201311 (\u201cConventional... basis\u201d)\n(\u201cConventional industrial agriculture has become incredibly efficient on a simple land to food basis.\u201d)", "lines 16\u201320 (\u201cAnd since... environment\u201d)\n(\u201cAnd since a third of the planet is already used for agriculture\u2014destroying forests and other wild habitats along the way\u2014anything that could help us produce more food on less land would seem to be good for the environment.\u201d)", "lines 39\u201341 (\u201cThey... widely\u201d)\n(\u201cThey found that organic farming delivered a lower yield for every crop type, though the disparity varied widely.\u201d)", "lines 48\u201351 (\u201cConventional... farming\u201d)\n(\u201cConventional agriculture makes use of 171 million metric tons of synthetic fertilizer each year, and all that nitrogen enables much faster plant growth than the slower release of nitrogen from the compost or cover crops used in organic farming.\u201d)"], "correct_answer_index": 3, "category": "Evidence Support Question"}, {"question": "According to Foley, an \u201cideal global agriculture system\u201d (line 62\n(\u201cideal global agriculture system,\u201d)\n)", "answers": ["focuses primarily on yield percentages and global markets.", "considers multiple factors in the selection of farming techniques.", "weighs the economic interests of farmers against the needs of consumers.", "puts the nutritional value of produce first and foremost."], "correct_answer_index": 1, "category": "Big Picture Question"}, {"question": "In line 68\n(\u201csheer\u201d)\n, \u201csheer\u201d most nearly means", "answers": ["transparent.", "abrupt.", "steep.", "pure."], "correct_answer_index": 3, "category": "Vocabulary in Context Question"}, {"question": "Which statement is best supported by the information provided in figure 1?", "answers": ["The organic yield as a percentage of conventional yield is greater for vegetables than for fruits.", "The organic yield as a percentage of conventional yield is similar for cereals and all crops.", "The reported number of observations for each crop type exceeds 82.", "The organic yield as a percentage of conventional yield is greater for vegetable crops than it is for oilseed crops."], "correct_answer_index": 1, "category": "Evidence Support Question"}, {"question": "Which of the following claims is supported by figure 2?", "answers": ["Of the organically grown species represented, soybeans have the lowest yield.", "The organically grown maize and barley represented are comparable in their yields to conventionally grown maize and barley.", "Of the organically grown species represented, tomatoes have the highest yield.", "The organically grown species represented have lower yields than their conventionally grown counterparts do."], "correct_answer_index": 3, "category": "Data Reasoning Question"}]}